readprint.com 2016-03-10

# Online Books, Poems, Short Stories - Read Print Library

Read Print (“ **Read Print** ”, “ **us** ” or “ **we** ”) respects the privacy of the users to its Website (“ **Users** ”), the home page of which is located at <http://www.readprint.com/> (“ **Website** ”). 

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of our policies and practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of any Personal Information and Anonymous Information you submit to us through our Website. If you have questions about this policy, email us at [privacy@readprint.com](mailto:privacy@readprint.com).

“ **Personal Information** ” is information about you that is personally identifiable to you like your name, address, e-mail address, or phone number, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing.

“ **Anonymous Information** ” means information that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Information; Anonymous Information does not permit the identification of individual persons. 

We collect and use Personal Information and Anonymous Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

**By submitting Personal Information through our Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Personal Information according to this Privacy Policy.**

**Your Personal Information may be processed by Read Print in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.**

## Information We Collect

#### 1\. Unregistered Users

We encourage you to register with us in order to take advantage of Read Print's many personalization features. However, you may choose not to register and take advantage of those features of our Website for which registration is not required.

If you do not register, we will only collect the following Anonymous Information from you:  
We may log your IP Address in order to help diagnose problems with our server, administer our Website and track usage statistics. An “ **IP Address** ” is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet.  In some cases your IP Address stays the same from browser session to browser session; but if you use a consumer internet access provider, your IP Address probably varies from session to session

We do not link your IP Address to any Personal Information to identify you.

If you reached our Website by clicking on a link or advertisement on another website, we log that information to help us maximize our Internet exposure, and to understand the interests of our Users.  
All of this information is collected and used only in the aggregate; that is, it is entered into our database, where we can use it to generate overall reports on the visitors of our Website, but not reports about individual Users.

We may also place a Cookie on your computer. “ **Cookies** ” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a website.  Read Print may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on the Website, to help us understand how Users use our Website, and to help us to improve our Website.  Persistent Cookies can be removed by following Internet browser help file directions. A Cookie may contain information that allows us to track your path through our Website and to determine whether you have visited us before. However, unless you register with us, it does not contain and is not linked to any Personal Information that would allow us to identify you. If you choose to disable Cookies, some areas of the Website (and other websites) may not work properly.

#### 2\. Registered Users

If you choose to register with us, you'll be able to add content to our Website. For example, you may post your own book reviews, create groups and lists as well as participate in our discussion forums. You will also be able to email content from the Website to yourself and others and to post information to various third-party websites, including popular social networks. In addition, you will benefit from the ability to personalize your Read Print experience.

If you register with us, we will collect Personal Information from you in addition to the Anonymous Information described above in the section “Unregistered Users”.

That Personal Information we collect from you may vary, depending on the features of the Website you use:

  * If you register as a User on the Website, we will collect  a username and password that you can choose and your e-mail address. If you wish to further personalize your Read Print account, you can choose what additional information you want to provide, such as a short biography of yourself, your favorite books, and your favorite authors, among other things. **Please note that any information that is stored in your Read Print account (with the exception of your password) can be seen by other Visitors of the Website, unless we have provided the option and you have selected it, to hide certain information from select groups of users on your Account Page. Please be aware of this fact and choose the information you want to provide accordingly.**
  * If you send us an email or get in contact with us using one of our online forms, we collect your email address and the content of your email or message.
  * If you participate in one of our online surveys, we will collect your response and might also collect additional information that you may decide to provide, such as, but not limited to, age, locations and other demographic information.

We may store Personal Information in a Cookie on your Computer, so that our Website will recognize you each time you visit our Website. In that way, we can save your preferences from visit to visit and present you with a customized Website, without requiring you to log into our Website every time you visit.

Additionally, authorized Read Print personnel may update your registration information to accurately reflect any new information included in communications received from you.

## Use of Personal Information we collect and your choices

We use the Personal Information we collect to personalize our Website so that it is most useful to you. It also allows you to log into our Website automatically each time you visit, rather than manually typing your user name and password every time.

We may also use this information to periodically contact you with news or important information from Read Print or to request your feedback on our site. In addition to these periodic updates, we may email you additional materials. These emails might include opt-in newsletters and other materials that you proactively request from Read Print.

In addition to these communications, if you have provided an email address, we may use your Personal Information to send you notifications about special offers or to tell you about opportunities available from our partners.  We will not provide any of our partners with information about you for their own marketing purposes, unless you ask us to do so.

In any case, we will only contact you as set forth above, if you request such communications from us. 

When you receive the aforementioned newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the email your receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below). You may change any of the Personal Information and your preferences regarding communications you want to receive from us by accessing and editing your account by visiting [http://www.readprint.com](http://www.readprint.com/), logging in, and then accessing your Account Page.

Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you administrative emails regarding our services or notices of any updates to our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy. If you want to opt-out from receiving such administrative emails, you have to deactivate your registration, as described below.

We may also use certain information that you provide in order to present you with advertising on our Website that you may find interesting. We might work together with third-party service providers to provide you with advertisements on our Website. Please be aware that clicking on such advertisements might lead you to other websites (please see the information regarding other websites below) and/or might place a Cookie on your computer.

**Cancellation of Registration**  
You can deactivate your registration with us by clicking on the link found on your Account Page.  We will confirm your request. After we receive confirmation, we will hide your information from our active database, but retain your information in our archives and backups so that, in the event you ever choose to re-activate your account, your old information is not lost. We may not be able to remove your information from our partners' databases, if we have transmitted any information to them as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**Posting information to public places**  
The idea behind Read Print is that the members of our community share information and knowledge. Therefore, you should assume that any information that you enter or post on the Website (not including the information in your Read Print account, with the exception of your username), may be openly shared on the Website with other community members and may also be available to people outside the community. Depending on where you post your information, you might be able to further specify which members or group of members of the Read Print community will be able to have access to this information. Please be aware that if you enter any Personal Information into publicly available sections of the Website, this information will be displayed to anyone who has access to these sections. These publicly available sections of the Website include, without limitation, the discussion forums, the review pages, comments, groups pages and others. Read Print also reserves the right to use your username in connection with any information you post to on the Website.

Members may also be able to search for publicly available information that was posted by a Read Print member in public sections of the Website, or for information in a Read Print account.

We may create Anonymous Information records from Personal Information by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the information personally identifiable to you.  We may use this Anonymous Information to analyze usage patterns so that we may enhance our community.  Read Print reserves the right to use and disclose Anonymous Information to third parties in its discretion. 

**Feedback**  
If you provide feedback to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided that we do not associate such feedback with your Personal Information.  Read Print will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the Personal Information in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Disclosure of your Personal Information.

Read Print does not sell or rent any personal information to any third party, other than our partners, as discussed in this Privacy Policy.

Although we currently do not have a parent company, any subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (collectively, “ **Affiliates** ”), we may in the future. We may share some of your Personal Information with these Affiliates, in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. Sharing this information allows us to better understand the ways in which our various product and service offerings can assist our Users. It also enables us to provide you with information about opportunities in which you might be interested.

We also may share your Personal Information with third parties specifically engaged by Read Print to provide services to Read Print (such as, but not limited to, market research firms, marketing services providers and advertising agencies), in which case we will require those parties to agree to use any such Personal Information solely for the purpose of providing the specified services to Read Print.

We may disclose your Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Read Print; or (b) to protect and defend the rights, safety, or property of Read Print, users of our Website, or third parties. If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

## Steps we take to protect your personal information.

Read Print has implemented security procedures to help protect the personal information stored in our systems. For example, we limit access to Personal Information about you to employees who we believe reasonably need to come into contact with that information. We also employ processes to protect against unauthorized access to your personal information. However, no company, including Read Print, can fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

## Children's Privacy

We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of thirteen (13).

**Other websites**  
Our provision of links to other websites or locations is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other websites or location or its contents. Links to other websites or locations may also be posted by other Read Print members within the Read Print community. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any substantial changes in the way we use your Personal Information, we will post an alert on this page.  If you object to any such changes, you must cease using our Website. Continued use of our Website following notice of any such changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

This Policy was last updated in September 2010.
